A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Program Management, Program Operations and Services, Assets Division, Office Files of Fred Tom FA685
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Program Management, Program Operations and Services, Assets Division, Office Files of Fred Tom
1984-2007
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA685
7.2 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Audit Files, 1984-2007; I
  - Audits (1) -- General Audit Information, Bangkok-Jakarta, 1994-2007 (Box 1)
    Arrangement
    Alphabetical
    Conditions Governing Access
    Some of the records in this file are restricted because they are less than 10 years old. The restricted items have been segregated and are inaccessible. The file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material is not necessary.
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015-2018.
  - Audits (2) -- Johannesburg-Nairobi, 1995-2007 (Box 1)
  - Audits (3) -- New Delhi, Rio de Janeiro, Santiago, Windhoek, 1997-2005 (Box 1)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015-2016.
  - Internal Audit -- Africa and the Middle East, 1996-2000 (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit -- Asia and Russia, 1993-2000 (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit -- Beijing, China, 1989-2004 (Box 2)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015.
  - Internal Audit -- Cairo, Egypt and Khartoum, Sudan, 1988-2004 (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit -- Hanoi, Vietnam, 1998-2005 (Box 2)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2016.
  - Internal Audit -- Jakarta, Indonesia, 1987-2005 (Box 2)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015 and 2016.
  - Internal Audit -- Johannesburg, South Africa, 1994-2004 (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit -- Lagos, Nigeria, 1989-2005 (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit -- Manila, Philippines, 1988-2003 (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit -- Mexico City, Mexico, 1987-2006 (Box 3)
    Some of the records in this file are restricted because they are less than 10 years old. The restricted items have been segregated and are inaccessible. The file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material is not necessary. Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015 and 2017.
  - Internal Audit -- Moscow, Russia, 1998-2005 (Box 3)
  - Internal Audit -- Nairobi, Kenya, 1988-2006 (Box 3)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015 and 2017.
  - Internal Audit -- New Delhi, India, 1984-2005 (Box 3)
  - Internal Audit -- PRI Audits -- FAPs, Grants to Organizations, Grants to Individuals, 1987-2003 (Box 3)
  - Internal Audit -- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1988-2005 (Box 3)
  - Internal Audit -- Santiago, Chile, 1992-2006 (Box 3)
  - Internal Audit -- Windhoek, Namibia, 1994-2001 (Box 3)
  - Internal Audit -- Other, 1993-1999 (Box 3)
- Regional Office Files, 1989-2006; II
  - Bangkok Field Office Visit (July 21-August 2, 1995) Briefing Book (folder 1), 1993-1995 (Box 4)
  - Bangkok Field Office Visit (July 21-August 2, 1995) Briefing Book (folder 2), 1993-1995 (Box 4)
  - Beijing Briefing Book, 1994-2001 (Box 4)
  - Brazil Briefing Book, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
  - Chile Briefing Book, 1993-2002 (Box 4)
  - Egypt Briefing Book, 1996-2003 (Box 4)
  - India Briefing Book, 1989-2002 (Box 4)
  - Kenya Briefing Book, 1995-2002 (Box 4)
  - Manila Briefing Book, 1989-2001 (Box 4)
  - Manila Briefing Book, 1989-2001 (Box 4)
  - Mexico City Briefing Book, 2001-2004 (Box 4)
  - Moscow Briefing Book (1998), 1996-2002 (Box 4)
  - Nigeria Briefing Book, 1994-2004 (Box 4)
  - South Africa Briefing Book, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - South Africa Briefing Book, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Vietnam Briefing Book, 1996-2002
  - Bangkok -- Office Closing, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Beijing -- Office Issues, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
    Some of the records in this file are restricted because they are less than 10 years old. The restricted items have been segregated and are inaccessible. The file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material is not necessary. Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2015.
  - Capital Projects Fiscal Year 1998 -- New Delhi Office, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Capital Projects Fiscal Year 2000, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Capital Projects Fiscal Year 2001, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Capital Projects Details Fiscal Year 2001 -- Re: Lagos Office (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Office Leases -- General Information, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Hanoi -- Visit (May 14-23, 1997) and Office Related Files, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Hanoi -- Vietnam Office, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
  - Hanoi -- Office Lease, Office Issues, Staff, Security, SARS Discusions, etc., 2001-2003 (Box 5)
  - Hanoi -- Vietnam Office -- Renovation (2006) and 2001 Lease, 2001-2007 (Box 5)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2017 and 2018.
  - Jakarta -- Office Visits, Office/Regional Issues, 1998-2005 (Box 5)
  - Jakarta, 1999-2005 (Box 5)
  - Johannesburg -- Capital Gains Tax, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Johannesburg -- Budget and Inventory, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Lagos -- GSO Lagos Trip (March 19-28, 1997), Mar 19-28, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Lagos, 2001-2006 (Box 5)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2017.
  - Lagos, 2002-2005 (Box 5)
  - Manila -- Office Closing, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
  - Mexico City, 2000-2005 (Box 6)
  - Mexico City -- Incl. Documents Re: Power Outage Situation, 2004-2005 (Box 6)
    File is closed to scholarly reserarch.
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Open to scholarly research in 2016.
  - Moscow -- Incl. Correspondence Re: Terrorism, 1996-2002 (Box 6)
  - Nairobi, 1996-2004 (Box 6)
  - New Delhi -- India Trip, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
  - New Delhi, 2003-2005 (Box 6)
  - Rio de Janeiro, 1998-2004 (Box 6)
  - Santiago, 1992-2005 (Box 6)
  - Santiago -- Grants Administration, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
  - Windhoek (Namibia) -- Office Closure, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
- Reports, 1985-2007; III
  - "Challenging the Assumptions: An Analysis of the Role of Evaluation in the Ford Foundation's Work in Forestry" by Anita Kendrick, 1985 (Box 6)
  - "Income and Employment in Bangladesh: Forward Ever Backward Never" by Marshall A. Bear and Jennefer Sebstad, Oct 1994 (Box 6)
  - "Evaluation of the Development Finance and Economic Security (DFES) Programme of the Ford Foundation, New Delhi Office" by Ajit Kanitkar and Shashi Rajagopalan, Oct 2005 (Box 6)
  - "Strategic Review of Sustainable Metropolitan Communities Initiative: Final Report" by Peter Plastrik and John Cleveland (slide presentation), Jun 24, 2006 (Box 6)
  - "Innovation: Individuals, Networks, Patronage" Draft by Stephen Kotkin -- An Evaluation of Higher Education Support in Russia, January-June 2006, Aug 2006 (Box 6)
  - "A Report on the Ford Foundation's Community Development Grantmaking, Andean Region and Southern Cone" by Julie C. Monteleone, Sep 2006 (Box 6)
  - "A Qualitative Review of the Impacts on the Organization" and "A Qualitative Review of External Impacts" Re: Forest Stewardship Council International Center, 2006-2007 (Box 6)
- Appendix A: Reports, 2006
  - Kotkin, Stephen; Innovation -- Individuals, Networks, Patronage, Aug 2006 (Report #019911)